In this lesson, we are gonna deal with responsive design.
这节课我们会讨论响应式设计
I have been using this word quite a bit in the previous lesson,
在前面的课程中 这个词我已经用了好几次
but without explaining it in a lot of detail.
但没有解释得很详细
Now, let's consider responsive design in detail and understand exactly what we
现在 让我们详细地探讨响应式设计 理解响应式设计的确切含义
mean by responsive design and how would you design a website to be responsive.
以及你该如何把网站设计为响应式
An immediate question that arises in our mind is,
那么马上问题就来了
why should we consider responsive design?
为什么我们要考虑响应式设计呢 ?
Why should we make our website responsive?
为什么我们要网站设计成响应式的呢 ?
When we look at how websites are being accessed these days,
当我们观察时下的网站是如何被访问的时候
you'll notice that people access websites from a variety of devices.
你会发现人们从各种不同的设备访问网站
All the way from desktops, laptops, tablets, down to mobile phones.
从台式机 笔记本电脑 平板电脑到手机都有
So, your website may be viewed by users using screens of different sizes.
所以 你的网站有可能被用户 以各种不同尺寸的屏幕浏览
If you design your website with a single screen size in mind,
如果你设计网站时只考虑一种尺寸
then it may render improperly or
那么它就有可能被不正确地渲染
completely unreadable on small screen devices.
又或者在屏幕小的设备上完全不可读
So if we can't proactively design our website to dramatically
因此如果我们可以主动地设计网站
adapt to the size of the screen from which the viewer is visiting
使其能灵活地适应浏览者的屏幕大小
your website, then that will make it a lot more easy for
浏览者就能更轻松地
the visitors to be able to see your website clearly.
清楚地浏览你的网站
Now, if they can build this feature into our website itself so
现在 如果我们可以将这个特性构建在网站本身
that it will automatically adapt to it's layout to the size of the screen from
让它能够自动调整布局去适应用户的屏幕尺寸
which the user is viewing your website, that that will be a great improvement.
那将会是一大改进
Responsive design aims to achieve this in practice.
响应式设计的目标就是在实践中实现这一目标
To do this, we're going to use the viewport property of our device,
要做到这一点 我们要用到设备的视域 (viewport) 属性
in order to adjust our website to the screen of the device.
来调整我们的网站到设备的屏幕上
The best way for
理解响应式设计的最好方法
us to understand responsive design is to take a look at an example.
是看一看例子
Let's have a look at the course website itself.
我们看看这个课程网站本身
So here you see the course website opened in a browser window.
你可以看到浏览器窗口开着课程网站
Now this window is I can bring the entire width of
我可以将它展开到整个屏幕的宽度
my screen which is currently 1280 pixels.
这个宽度现在是1280像素
Suppose I view the same website from a device,
设想我要用一个设备来浏览同一个网站
which has a much smaller screen say about 700 pixels,
这个设备的屏幕只有大概700像素
how would these website be rendered in those circumstances?
这种情况下网站应该如何被渲染呢
To help us to understand this better,
为了帮助更好地我们理解
what I'm going to do is to just shrink the size of my browser so
我要做的是缩小浏览器的尺寸
that my website will automatically adapt itself to the size of the browser.
让网站自动调整到浏览器的尺寸
So, in some way, I am simulating accessing the website
这样 从某些方面来说 我就是在模仿
from the basis of different screen sizes.
从不同尺寸的屏幕访问网站的效果
So at this moment, this would be a 1,200 pixel screen size.
现在 屏幕的宽度是1200像素
Which would be equivalent to a typical laptop these days.
这相当于时下的一台笔记本电脑的典型尺寸
Now, let's look at what the website looks like if you were accessing it from
让我们看看用平板电脑的横屏状态
a tablet in the landscape position.
来访问这个网站时的效果
So, perhaps, that looks more like the size of the screen from a tablet.
也许这样看起来比较像平板电脑的屏幕尺寸
This is typical tablet landscape sizes are around 700 to sometimes even much higher
典型平板电脑的横屏尺寸大约在700像素左右
pixel sizes these days, but maybe a seven inch older
有些设备的尺寸会更大 而较旧的七吋笔记本电脑
laptop perhaps has a width of about 800 pixels.
可能会有800像素左右的屏幕宽度
So, this is what your website will look like on a tablet.
所以 这就是你的网站在平板电脑上看起来的样子
Let's continue shrinking the browser window, and
让我们继续缩小浏览器窗口
see how the website will look like at even more smaller sizes.
看看网站在更小的尺寸上看起来是怎样的
So as you keep shrinking the window size, notice how the contents of the website
当你继续缩小窗口尺寸的时候 留意网站的内容
is automatically adapting itself to the size of the screen.
会自动适应屏幕的尺寸
Now, you notice that when I shrank it below a certain point, there was a sudden
现在 留意当我将窗口缩小到某一个特定大小的时候
change in the way the website was being shown on the screen in the browser window.
网站在浏览器窗口中显示的方式会发生一个突然的变化
So let's see, we have here, and then a little step further down you
我们来看一下 我们在这个尺寸 然后只要再缩小一点点
suddenly notice that the website has rendered some more differently you
你会突然发现网站渲染得不一样了
see that the navigation bar at the top of the window has disappeared,
你可以看到窗口顶部的导航栏已经消失
instead to be replaced by a button on the left side.
被左侧的一个按钮代替了
Now the navigation bar is still accessible.
现在导航栏依然是可访问的
When you click on the button,
当你点击那个按钮的时候
you now see a sidebar pop up with the information that used
会弹出一个侧边栏 上面的信息
to be in the sidebar of your website for larger screen size.
就是刚才较大的屏幕上 网站侧边栏上的信息
Now this side bar has been hidden at this screen size.
现在侧边栏在这个屏幕尺寸上被隐藏了
So, now I can hide this by simply clicking at any other location.
我可以点击任意其他位置来隐藏这个侧边栏
Also note how the contents of the website have
另外 留意网站的内容
adapted themselves to the screen size.
也自动调整到屏幕的尺寸
So, this would be like a tablet, perhaps, in its portrait position.
这就如同平板电脑 在横向摆放时的效果
Let's continue to shrink the website window down.
让我们继续缩小网站窗口的尺寸
And use you see how the contents of the website are automatically adapting itself.
你可以看到网站内容是如何自动调整的
And as we scroll through the website,
当我们滚动网站的时候
you see that the contents have adapted themselves to the size of
你可以看到它的内容已经调整到
the browser window here, or equivalently to the size of the screen.
浏览器窗口的尺寸 或者说 相当于屏幕的尺寸
How is this possible?
这是怎么发生的呢
This is where responsive design comes to our rescue.
这就是响应式设计的威力了
Another term you will often hear people talking about
另外一个你常常会听人提起的
in the context of responsive design is Mobile First.
响应式设计范畴内的术语是移动优先
What exactly is Mobile First design?
确切来说 什么是移动优先式设计?
Traditionally, when people were designing their websites for
传统上 当人们设计网站 需要这个网站同时兼顾
both larger screen
大屏幕设备
windowed devices like laptops and desktops and smaller screens,
如笔记本电脑 台式电脑 和小屏幕设备时
they would often do the layout for the larger screens first, and then try to
他们常常会先设计大屏幕下的布局
adapt their content to be appropriately displayed on the smaller screen.
然后再尝试调整网站的内容 使其在小屏幕上也能恰当地显示
So in this diagram here that you see the traditional approach would have been first
因此在这幅图中 传统的方法会是
to design for a laptop and then adapt the content
先给笔记本电脑设计 再调整内容
to fit into the smaller window size.
去适应更小的窗口尺寸
Increasingly, people are adopting the mobile first approach.
现在 人们越来越多地采用移动优先的方法
What this means is that you first design your website with the mobile
意思是你设计网站时 首先考虑的是
screen size in mind.
移动设备的屏幕尺寸
First, do all your layout for the mobile screen size, and
首先为移动设备的屏幕设计网站布局
then start adapting your website design for larger screen sizes.
之后再为更大的屏幕尺寸调整网站设计
So as your screen size expands the content will automatically flow and
这样 当你的屏幕尺寸扩大时 内容会自动流动
then adjust itself to occupy the larger
并调整到占据更大屏幕的设备
width of the screen that becomes available on larger screen devices.
所带来的更宽的屏幕宽度
In order to achieve mobile first design,
为了达到移动优先式设计
there are three things that need to come together.
需要有三样东西的支持
First, your front end UI framework should be able to support a grid based system.
第一 你的前端界面框架应该支持网格系统
This has been increasingly been opted by most front end UI frameworks.
它已经越来越多地被大部分前端界面框架所支持
So look at anyone of the front end frameworks that is in use, and
因此当我们观察任意一个通行的前端框架
you will see that they will have some kind of support for a grid-based system.
都会发现它以某种形式支持网格系统
We'll look at grid-based systems, in particular the Bootstrap Grid,
我们会在下一堂课里更详细地
in more detail in the next lecture.
探讨网格系统 尤其是Bootstrap网格 (Bootstrap Grid)
The second aspect is to have fluid images,
第二方面是要有流动图像
or what we call responsive images, so you can make your
又称为响应式图像的支持 这样你就可以
website images automatically adapt to the size of the screen.
使网站上的图片自动根据屏幕尺寸调整大小
So this again has to be built-in.
这又是一个必须内嵌的特性
Bootstrap has good support for fluid images or
Bootstrap 已经在它的 CSS 类中为流动图像
responsive images already available within the Bootstrap CSS classes.
或称响应式图像提供了很好的支持
We'll examine that in more detail in the next module.
我们会在下一章中更详细地探讨这个话题
The third kind of support that is required is what we call media queries.
第三种我们所需要的支持叫做媒体查询 (media queries)
If you remember, in the previous slide I had mentioned about the viewport.
如果你还记得 在前一张幻灯片里 我提到了视域
Using the viewport, you can get a sense of the size of
通过视域 你可以大致感受到
the screen that is being being used to view your website.
用来浏览你网站的屏幕的尺寸
So for mobile devices, using the view port properly,
对于移动设备来说 如果恰当地使用视域
you would be able to realize that the screen size is fairly small,
你应该能够发觉屏幕屏幕尺寸相当小
say around 700 pixels or even lesser than that.
只有约700像素 甚至比这更小
And for larger screen sizes, obviously, you can adapt.
而对于更大的屏幕尺寸来说 很明显 你可以调适
Now, this can be used to our advantage by putting in media queries and
通过在CSS类的设计中加入媒体查询并且加以利用
using media queries in our CSS class design.
视域会很有帮助
How is this achieved in practice?
在实践中这要如何达成呢
Media queries uses an approach where,
媒体查询通过这样的方法实现
within your CSS file, you will define slightly different variations for
在你的CSS文件中 根据不同的窗口尺寸
each of the CSS classes depending on the size of the window being used.
你可以将每个CSS类定义得稍有不同
To conduct a media query,
要进行一次媒体查询
you would include a statement like this in your CSS file.
你要在你的CSS文件中加入像这样的一条语句
You would say, @media and screen, and you can specify the minimum width.
你会写 @media 和 screen 然后指明最小的宽度
And inside these braces for
然后在这条媒体查询的花括号内
this media query, you can specify the CSS styles that are applicable
你可以列举一些CSS样式 这些样式
only if the minimum width of the screen is about six, 600 pixels.
只会在屏幕宽度在600像素以上时才适用
So like this you can design the CSS tiles for different screen sizes.
像这样你就可以设计不同的CSS代码给不同的屏幕尺寸
So, for example, in Bootstrap as we will see later,
例如 在Bootstrap里 就像我们稍后会看到的那样
you will have media queries which will redesign the CSS classes,
有的媒体查询会重新设计CSS类
or rather adapt the CSS classes for different screen widths.
有的则会将CSS类因应不同的屏幕宽度作调整
To help us understand better, I have brought up the bootstrap.css file for
为了帮助我们更好地理解 我打开了bootstrap.css文件
our project that we had designed I opened the bootstrap.css
这个文件曾经用在我们之前设计的项目中
file in brackets, and you can see that I have scrolled inside this file
我用Brackets打开bootstrap.css文件 你可以看到我已经滚动到文件中
to a location where a media query is present.
一个有媒体查询的位置
So, looking at the code here,
看看这里的代码
you'll see that it says media min-width is 1,200 pixels,
你会看到这里写着 @media (min-width: 1200px)
and if the minimum width of the screen is 1,200 pixels,
如果屏幕的最小宽度是1200像素
then I am going to define my container to be 1,170 pixels.
我就将我的container的宽度定义为1170像素
So this is one way you can adapt your CSS
这是你将你的CSS类
classes to the size of the screen.
调整到屏幕尺寸的一种方式
So, a media query like this included your CSS file will enable
因此 将这样的媒体查询包含到你的CSS文件里
your CSS classes to be redefined for different screen sizes.
可以让你的CSS类根据不同的屏幕尺寸重新定义
This is one way to implement responsive design within your project.
这是在你的项目中实现响应式设计的一种方式
Now, you're going to ask yourselves, oh that seems so difficult to do.
现在 你可能会问自己 哎呀 这看起来好难
There are so many things to track,
有那么多东西要追踪
and how do I make sure that everything works correctly?
我又怎么能保证所有东西都正确地运作呢
Don't worry.
别担心别担心
As a novice you might want to start with a pre-designed
作为新手 你也许想要从那些已经预先设计好的
front end UI framework like Bootstrap.
前端界面框架 如Bootstrap 开始入手
They have already done the heavy lifting for you.
他们已经为你减轻了大部分的负担
They have already designed the classes to be responsive,
预先设计好了响应式的类
so you can start with that and once you get more comfortable with
你可以先从这些定义好的类开始入手 而一旦你已经熟悉了
these CSS queries and various features, then you can go in and
这些CSS查询和各种不同的特性之后 你就可以
tweak the files to suit your specific needs.
着手去改变这些文件来满足你的特定需求 翻译: LIYB  | 审阅: Saul Qunming Yuan Coursera Global Translator Community